Maggie Benston fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Maggie Benston fonds
1966 - 1972
F-126
Q103827254
77 cm of textual records 18 newspapers
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Benston, Maggie
Maggie Benston (1937-1991) was a Professor of Chemistry, Computing Science, and Women's Studies at SFU. A respected feminist and community activist, she was a founding member of the Vancouver Women's Caucus.
published
Full
Revised
Title of fonds based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records reflecting the academic and personal interests of Maggie Benston. The fonds is arranged in 5 series: Research files, Women's Caucus, Subject files, Publications, and Personal documents.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Science and technology; Women
The papers in this fonds were brought to the Archives by a graduate student who had used them for her research. The papers are made available for research with the permission of Dr. Marian Lowe, Dr. Benston's sister.
All accessions have been processed as of March 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Also see the inventory for Maggie Benston Collection / Sue Cox (collector), F-69.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. An item is list has been produced for the periodicals in series 4.
Biographical information is included in the appendix.
- Research files, 1967 - 1970; F-126-1; 6 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to Maggie Benston's research interests on feminist topics including her seminal paper, "On the Political Economy of Women's Liberation." Includes correspondence regarding the publication of this paper, drafts of the paper, manuscript notes for a follow-up article and book, daily notebooks and other documents.
  - Manuscript notes 1/2, 1969 - 1970; F-126-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Manuscript notes 2/2, 1969 - 1970; F-126-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Drafts - The Political Economy of Women's Liberation, [ca 1967] - [ca 1969]; F-126-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Correspondence, 1969; F-126-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Correspondence, 1970; F-126-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Daily notebooks, 1969 - 1970; F-126-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - News clippings about Maggie Benston, 1969 - 1970; F-126-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
- Women's Caucus, 1966 - 1971; F-126-2; 22 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the history, organization, and activities of the Vancouver Women's Caucus. This group, which started at Simon Fraser University in 1968, moved off campus in 1969 in order to focus on broader community interests. Most active until 1971, the group eventually divided into issue oriented organizations. Includes minutes, membership lists, discussion papers and other documents.
  Vancouver Women's Caucus
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Berkeley and Bay Area, [ca 1969] - 1971; F-126-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Conferences, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Discussion papers, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - History and activities, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Minutes, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Membership, 1969; F-126-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - News clippings - Vancouver and Canada, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - Newsletters, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 126-1)
  - PSA (Political Science, Sociology, Anthropology) Department, 1969; F-126-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Press Releases, 1970; F-126-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Socialism and politics, [ca 1967] - 1971; F-126-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Students, 1969; F-126-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Vietnam, 1966; F-126-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - voice of the women's liberation movement news, 1969; F-126-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women academics, 1968; F-126-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women in the labour and work force, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women's liberation for teachers, 1971; F-126-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women's liberation for teachers: questionnaire, 1971; F-126-2-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women's liberation - US and elsewhere, 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 126-2)
  - Women's liberation - Berkeley (S.P.A.Z.M.), 1969 - 1970; F-126-2-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Women's liberation - Toronto, 1970; F-126-2-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - YS/LSA split (Young Socialists and the League for Socialist Action), 1970; F-126-2-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
- Subject files, 1967 - 1970; F-126-3; 10 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Maggie Benston's many personal and professional interests such as the women's movement, environmental issues and socialism. Includes publications, reports, clippings and other documents.
  - Abortion, 1969 - 1970; F-126-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Beauty contests, 1969 - 1970; F-126-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Channeling of women, 1968 - 1969; F-126-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Child care, 1969 - 1970; F-126-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Hogtown Press and other publishers, 1969; F-126-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Men, 1969; F-126-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Pollution, 1967 - 1968; F-126-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Pollution clippings, 1969 - 1970; F-126-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Pollution clippings - Chemistry 101, 1969; F-126-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
  - Socialism - international, 1970; F-126-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 126-3)
- Publications collected by Maggie Benston, 1969 - 1972; F-126-4; 35 cm of textual records 18 newspapers
  Series consists of various publications relating to women's issues as collected by Margaret Benston. See item list for complete list of all periodicals.
  - Guardian - independent radical newsweekly, February 1969; F-126-4-0-0-0-1 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item1.
  - Workers World, vol. 12 no. 4, March 1970; F-126-4-0-0-0-2 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item2.
  - It Ain't Me Babe, vol. 1 no. 3, February 1969; F-126-4-0-0-0-3 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item3.
  - It Ain't Me Babe, vol. 1 no. 2, January 1969; F-126-4-0-0-0-4 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item4.
  - Le journal jaune, vol. 1 no. 9, October 1970; F-126-4-0-0-0-5 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item5.
  - Leviathan, vol. 2 no. 1, May 1970; F-126-4-0-0-0-6 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item6.
  - Off Our Backs, vol. 1 no. 9-10, July 1970; F-126-4-0-0-0-7 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item7.
  - RAT Suberranean News, vol. 2 no. 28, February 1970; F-126-4-0-0-0-8 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item8.
  - Sisterhood: A special edition of The Ubyssey, vol. 52 no. 29, February 1971; F-126-4-0-0-0-9 (Newspaper box 126-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-4-0-2, F-126-item9.
  - The Pedestal, published by Vancouver Women's Caucus, 1969 - 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1 (Newspaper box 126-5)
    - The Pedestal, vol. 1 no. 1, 1969; F-126-4-0-0-1-10 (Newspaper box 126-5)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item10.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 1 no. 2, 1969; F-126-4-0-0-1-11 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item11.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 4, May 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-12 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item12.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 5, June 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-13 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item13.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 6, July 1970 - August 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-14 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item14.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 7, September 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-15 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item15.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 8, October 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-16 (Newspaper box 126-5)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item16.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 9, October 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-17 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item17.
    - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 10, December 1970; F-126-4-0-0-1-18 (Newspaper box 126-6)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-126-item18.
  - Various publications, 1969 - 1971; F-126-4-0-0-2 (Newspaper box 126-4)
  - The Pedestal, Vol 1, no 1, Vol 2, no 4-7, 1966-1970; F-126-4-0-0-3 (126-7)
  - Publications re Women's Liberation Movement, 1969-1972, F-126-4-0-0-4 (126-8)
- Personal documents, 1966-1970; F-126-5; 4 cm of textual records
  Series consists of Benston's personal correspondence with relatives, Louis Feldhammer, as well as information regarding a libel suit and salary pay scales from 1966.
  - Personal correspondence, 1969-1970; F-126-5-0-0-1 (126-8)
  - Correspondence with Louis Feldhammer, 1970; F-126-5-0-0-2 (126-8)
    Restricted until December 31, 2027
  - Mitzman v Benston et. al libel suit, 1970; F-126-5-0-0-3 (126-8)
  - Faculty salary and map of Saltspring Island, 1966; F-126-5-0-0-4 (126-8)